<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on The history of Peterhouse Boat Club</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on The history of Peterhouse Boat Club</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://history.peterhousebc.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Foreword</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/_foreword/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/_foreword/</guid><description>FOREWORD # Most of the best experiences in life come as surprises. Apart from being elected Master of Peterhouse, nothing has come as a greater surprise to me than to find myself President of the Peterhouse Boat Club. As a non-rowing man I have had a lot to learn. Among other things I have come to appreciate the truth of Professor Martin Plumley’s assertion at a recent Bumps Supper that there is nothing much wrong with a college when its boats are doing well.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/_introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/_introduction/</guid><description>INTRODUCTION # On April 29 1828 some men of St. Peter’s College - their names seem to be past recovery - joined the bumping races on the Cam which had been officially established in the previous year. Except for an intermission from 1833-5, in 1836, and during the Great War the activity of the boat club is unbroken. It is not only one of the oldest of the college boat clubs, but is the longest lasting undergraduate society in Peterhouse.</description></item><item><title>1828 – 1842</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1828-1842/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1828-1842/</guid><description>1828 – 1842 # In a little book called ‘Facetiae Cantabrigienses’ there is an account of a water-party, dated 1822; some men of various colleges hired a six-oar, the ‘Glory’, from Cross, and rowed to ‘Backsbite’ lock; on the way they encountered the ‘Stag’ and raced her side by side. This seems to be the first account of an undergraduate race on the Cam. But rather like our colleges and University, bumping races were an importation from Oxford.</description></item><item><title>1843 – 1849</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1843-1849/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1843-1849/</guid><description>1843 – 1849 # In March of 1843 it was resolved to buy a new boat, and about £52 were subscribed. It is noticeable from the minutes that despite this high cost which fell directly upon the members, the Club tried to buy a new boat every few years, even annually. The bumping was often ferocious and not uncommonly in histories of this period boats are described as ‘written off’.</description></item><item><title>1850 – 1864</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1850-1864/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1850-1864/</guid><description>1850 – 1864 # In October of 1850 six new members were elected, among them E.J. Routh. He was Senior Wrangler in 1854 and during his time as a Fellow the most successful mathematical coach of his day; a replica of the Herkomer portrait hangs in the Hall. Apart from some motions concerning dress the year passed without incident.
In the October term of 1851 the Club joined with Sidney to enter a crew in the ‘Varsity four oared race, which had been founded in 1849.</description></item><item><title>1865 – 1879</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1865-1879/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1865-1879/</guid><description>1865 – 1879 # In October 1865 there were eleven new members of whom R. Waltham won his Blue for putting the weight. Another, J.G. Barnes, later Lord Gorell, was President of the Probate, Divorce and Admiralty Division of the High Court. The Club was £100 in debt but a subscription was deferred. It was proposed, but not carried, to row the scratch fours in academicals. In the Lent term of 1866 college trial eights certainly rowed and they were to become regular.</description></item><item><title>1880 – 1914</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1880-1914/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1880-1914/</guid><description>1880 – 1914 # In the Michaelmas term of 1880 there were two new members elected who distinguished themselves in ‘Varsity sports: J.G. Tait, the Club’s Secretary in October 1882, was a Rugby Blue (his father, Professor Tait, was a member in 1852); and F.H. Rawlins became President of the University Swimming Club. Light ships were not being rowed thanks to a CUBC ruling. Trial eights were cancelled because many men had gone out of residence to avoid sickness.</description></item><item><title>1919 – 1939</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1919-1939/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1919-1939/</guid><description>1919 – 1939 # The Great War put a stop to all the undergraduate life of Cambridge. On February 2 1919 a general meeting of the Amalgamation Club set about re¬organizing college sports. There were twelve members only in the boat club, and a crew, made up of Naval officers, rowed in that term’s special fixed-seat races, which were conducted in groups on the American tournament system. In the May term of 1919 it was proposed to re-introduce the old (?</description></item><item><title>1940 – 1956</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1940-1956/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1940-1956/</guid><description>1940 – 1956 # The second outbreak of ‘furor Teutonicus’ did not put a complete stop to undergraduate life. A handful of men were in residence and the PBC fared well during the war. For those six years the London School of Economics, rowing under its own colours, was the Club’s guest. If there was any racing between Michaelmas 1939 and Lent 1941 no record of it has been preserved.</description></item><item><title>1957 – 1978</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1957-1978/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/01_mayer__ambrose/1957-1978/</guid><description>1957 – 1978 # The next twenty years can only be glanced at. The difficulties in which the PBC found itself were not irremediable. The officers in May of 1959, for example, looked proudly upon the consolidation of some fifty oarsmen after a Michaelmas that saw only eleven members and no freshmen. Their policy paid off in the bumps of 1960, and decline was arrested. In the Lent term of 1963 the ice was six inches thick on the Long Reach.</description></item></channel></rss>