<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>You can win this, you know! on The history of Peterhouse Boat Club</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/</link><description>Recent content in You can win this, you know! on The history of Peterhouse Boat Club</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Appendix 1. Tom's closing thoughts</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/appendix_1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/appendix_1/</guid><description>Appendix 1. Tom&amp;rsquo;s closing thoughts # One is tempted to use the title of Haydn&amp;rsquo;s Opus 51 quartets, but that would be inappropriate.
Tom wrote, on July 25^th,^ &amp;lsquo;56, a letter which began in typical Tom fashion:
&amp;quot;&amp;hellip; I can assure you that the thanks are all mine. I have never, I can sincerely say, had a happier time than coaching the Peterhouse crew at Cambridge and Henley.
My fear all along was that I would not do you justice.</description></item><item><title>Appendix 2. Reassurance</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/appendix_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/appendix_2/</guid><description>Appendix 2. Reassurance. (not sure I have all this right &amp;ndash; may be revised) # Our riverine experiences taught us all that no matter how unlikely success might seem, hard work and determination could get the job done. So what happened in later life to those 12 guys who were all together in the right place at the right time?
Martin Bartlett Practiced medicine in the U.S and Australia, returning to the U.</description></item><item><title>Appendix 3. More memories</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/appendix_3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/appendix_3/</guid><description>Appendix 3. More memories (in the order received) # From Chris Calladine, regarding instructions given to Danny Taylor:
&amp;ldquo;Yes, Roy Lubbock was the senior Fellow and the Engineering don (since 1919). As told me by someone (possibly Danny), he told Danny not to worry too much about super-vising engineering students, but to put his back into coaching the VIII. Roy told me that when he saw the Ladies' plate which you brought to the college, he immediately recognised it: it stood on his housemaster's mantle-piece when he was a new boy at Eton!</description></item><item><title>Appendix 4. Club spirit -- the Mitchell Cup, Rugger Boats and such matters.</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/appendix_4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/appendix_4/</guid><description>Appendix 4. Club spirit &amp;ndash; the Mitchell Cup, Rugger Boats and such matters. # It has been said by more than one Master, that &amp;ldquo;If the boat club is healthy, so is the College.&amp;rdquo; The Mitchell Cup is a measure of that health, and Peterhouse has been high in the standings many times.
May 1956 # On display were trophies for C.U.B.C. Clinker IVs, Fairbairn Junior Sculls, Lowe Double Sculls, Bedford Junior Sculls, College Junior and Senior Sculls, London Rowing Club Colleges Regatta, and of course the Fairbairn Cup and the C.</description></item><item><title>Appendix 5. Reaching even further towards our good beginning</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/appendix_5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/appendix_5/</guid><description>Appendix 5. Reaching even further towards our good beginning # Patrick Overy dug this out from the depths of &amp;ldquo;Ernie&amp;rsquo;s shop.&amp;rdquo; The Lent crew of 1873.
Tim Ambrose&amp;rsquo;s graphs show a rise of three places that year, after a precipitous fall and before another descent, so they had something to be proud of. Must have been a strange time &amp;ndash; low numbers, but enormous science and math influence. Cookson was Master.</description></item><item><title>Appendix 6. About Captaincy and how our smallest college still has a chance, even given today's challenges.</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/appendix_6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/appendix_6/</guid><description>Appendix 6. About Captaincy and how our smallest college still has a chance, even given today&amp;rsquo;s challenges. # All of the foregoing, our fun story about winning, leads us back to W.G.Herten&amp;rsquo;s advice to Captains. So much has changed on the river and even more has changed in our society, that one can only wonder how on earth he would approach the subject today. What can WE leave behind to guide incoming Captains?</description></item><item><title>Download PDF</title><link>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/download_pdf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://history.peterhousebc.org/docs/03_you_can_win_this_you_know/download_pdf/</guid><description>Download PDF.</description></item></channel></rss>